Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Africa Serials TAM.782
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Africa Serials
1951-2009
1970-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.782
1.8 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 flat box
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Africa Serials contains over 50 titles published in Africa, the United States, and Europe on political, cultural, and social issues in sub-Saharan Africa between 1951 and 2009. The bulk of the collection consists of serials published between the 1970s and the 1980s on South Africa and anti-apartheid movements in Africa, the United States, and the United Kingdom.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to Africa drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Africa Serials contains over 50 titles published in Africa, the United States (US), and Europe on political, cultural, and social issues in sub-Saharan Africa between 1951 and 2009. The bulk of the collection consists of serials published between the 1970s and the 1980s. Topics include political, cultural, and social issues in South Africa, Angola, Ethiopia, Ghana, Nigeria, and Kenya in the mid to late 20th century. The bulk of the collection focuses on human rights issues in South Africa and anti-apartheid movements in South Africa, the US, and the United Kingdom (UK) in the 1970s and 1980s. Other topics include the liberation movement in Angola in the 1970s, the Ethiopian Civil War, and organizations formed by African students in the US and UK.
Apartheid -- South Africa.; Serials (publications); Africa -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Anti-apartheid movements -- 20th century -- Periodicals.
- Afram Newsletter: Centre d'Etudes Afro-Americaines et des Litteratures Anglophones de l'University Paris III (Sorbonne Nouvelle), Paris, France, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- African Literature Association, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- African Review: New Africa Publications, Ltd., Accra, Ghana, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- African Studies in America - the Extended Family: Africa Research Group, Cambridge, MA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Afrique XX1: Afrique XX1, Quincy-sous-Senart, France, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Angola in Arms: People's Movement for the Liberation of Angola, Richmond, BC, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Angola News Summary: MPLA Solidarity Committee, New York, NY, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Angola Newsletter: United Students for the Liberation of Angola and Southern Africa, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Angola Update: Fenton Communications, Inc., Washington, DC, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Anti-Apartheid News: Anti-Apartheid Movement, London, UK, 1991 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 1)
- Apri News Release: A. Philip Randolph Institute, New York, NY, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Azania News: Pan Africanist Congress, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Beyond Relief: African Development Foundation, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Boycott News, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 2)
- Challenge: Ethiopian Students of North America, New York, NY, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Combat: Ethiopian Students in North America, Atlanta, GA, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Episcopal Churchmen for South Africa: New York, NY, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Fact Paper on South Africa: International Defence & Aid Fund, London, UK, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Finally Got The News: African Liberation Support, Washington, DC, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Freedom Fighter: Southern Africa Solidarity Campaign, London, UK, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Full Frame: Afrapix, Johannesburg, South Africa, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Growth of Co-operatives in Zambia 1914-71: University of Zambia Institute for Social Research, Lusaka, Zambia, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Horizon: ANC Youth League, South Africa, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- I.D.A.F. News Notes: United States Committee of International Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, Cambridge, MA, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ikwezi: Nottingham, UK, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Institute for Social Research: University of Zambia Institute for Social Research, Lusaka, Zambia, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Namibia News: South West African People's Organisation, London, UK, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- New Ghana: Ghana Information Services, Ghana, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- NISER Reprint Series #3: Nigerian Institute of Social & Economic Research, Ibadan, Nigeria, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Ogoni Gong: Ogoni Soidarity Forum, Cape Town, South Africa, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Omkeer: The Paper for Call-Up Age South Africans: South African Liberation Support Committee (SALSCOM), Brooklyn, NY, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Pan Africa: Pan-African Press Limited, Nairobi, Kenya, 1963 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 3)
- Presence Africaine: Fairth Quarterly, Paris, France, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Proceedings: National Anti-C.A.D. Committee, Cape Town, South Africa, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Race Relations News: SA Institute of Race Relations, Johannesburg, South Africa, 1970 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 4)
- Resister: Bulletin of the Committee on South African War Resistance: Committee on South African War Resistance, London, UK, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
- Revolution in Africa: Material Aid Campaign for Zanu, New York, NY, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rhodes-Livingstone Papers: Manchester University Press, Lusaka, Zambia, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- SAMRAF News & Notes: South African Military Refugee Aid Funding, Brooklyn, NY, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Science-Afrique: Commission for Technical Co-operation in Africa South of the Sahara, London, UK, 1958-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- South Africa Alert: A. Philip Randolph Institute, New York, NY, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Southern Africa Solidarity: Southern Africa Solidarity, Cambridge, MA, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Spark: Southern Africa Solidarity Campaign, London, UK, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Spearhead: Afreepress Limited, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Struggle: New York Chapter ESUNA, New York, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- TCLSAC: Toronto Committee for the Liberation of Southern Africa, Toronto, Ontario, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Torch: Torch Printing and Publishing Co. (Pty.) Ltd., Cape Town, South Africa, 1951 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 5)
- Transkei Ekonomiese-Economic Revue: Bureau for Economic Research and Bantu Development, Pretoria, South Africa, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- United Nations Centre Against Apartheid: Peace Education Division of the American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Voice of Africa: Bureau of African Affairs, Accra, Ghana, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Weekly News Briefing: African National Congress of South Africa, London, UK, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Zambian Urban Studies: University of Zambia Institute for Social Research, Lusaka, Zambia, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Zimbabwe Review: African National Council, Zimbabwe, Lusaka, Zambia, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)